Pablo Bolaños

Front-end Developer



- 🔀 izrael.parraga@gmail.com
- **L** +593 0963662069
- Riobamba, Ecuador
- in Linkedin
- GitHub



- Mastery of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, Git
- Knowledge of Frameworks such as Angular JS, Agular Material, Bootstrap, PrimeNG
- Knowledge of programming languages such as C++, C#, Java
- Use of the Jira management tool
- Adaptability and continuous learning



Spanish

English



CERTIFICATES

• Angular: De cero a experto - Edición 2023 🗗

INTERESTS

- Video games
- Go hiking
- Swimming
- Cooking

DESCRIPTION

My passion for computer programing has been since I was in high school. I have been able to further develop my skills in Computer Programming while learning other facets within the same releam. I have been able to learn various other programming language but my current focus is in Web Development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web developer

DTIC - ESPOCH

02/2023 - present | Riobamba, Ecuador

- Developed and maintained several web applications using JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, Angular, Angular Material.
- Worked closely with the UI/UX team to design and implement responsive and dynamic user interface.
- Implement advance functionalities such as form validation, routing, and data visualization.
- Collaborate with the back-end team to ensure seamless integration between front-end and back-end systems.

Web developer

BUNUELOS DIAZ

06/2020 - 09/2021 | Riobamba, Ecuador

- Created a reusable component library for the web application using Angular Material, resulting in faster development time for new features.
- Optimized website speed and performance by implementing lazy loading, code splitting and other techniques.
- Contributed to the development of the company's internal front-end and best practices.
- Developed bakery website using web technologies like, HTML, CSS, Typescript, Angular.

Web Developer

MELASOFT

10/2021 - 02/2023 | Riobamba, Ecuador

- Encourage collaboration and constant communication among team members.
- User interface design and web design with HTML and CSS.
- Page cleanup and repair of broken links or images.
- Technical support to the complete project cycle from web design,
- Layout, development, programming and final publication.

EDUCATION

Software Engineer

Escuela Superior Politécnica de Chimborazo 10/2018 – present | Riobamba, Ecuador